你在忙什么呢
What are you working on?
没空说话  专注模式中
Can't talk. In the zone.
你知道他在忙什么吗
Do you know what he's doing?
有各种可能
Could be anything.
上次像这样时
Last time he was like this,
他解决了石墨烯中的电子传递问题
he figured out electron transport in graphene.
再之前的那次  他列了一张
The time before that, he was making a list
如果他有树屋  谁可以上去玩的名单
of who's allowed in his tree fort if he ever gets one.
至今不敢相信我居然落选了
Still can't believe I didn't make the cut.
谢尔顿  要休息一下吗
Uh, Sheldon, you want to take a break?
吃的来了哦
Your food's ready.
别这样  你干什么呢
No, no, what are you doing?
他现在既开心又安静
He's both happy and quiet.
就像同时看到独角兽和大野人一样罕见
It's like seeing a unicorn and Bigfoot at the same time.
抱歉我们来晚了
Sorry we're so late.
伯纳黛特工作太忙走不开
Bernadette got stuck at work.
重大好消息
Great news!
一种浣熊病毒刚刚打破了种族障碍
A raccoon virus just crossed the species barrier
现在可以传染给人类了
and now can infect humans!
这算什么重大好消息
Why is that great news?
在医药界我们有种说法
In the pharmaceutical business, we have a saying:
"传染越多  赚钱越多"
"Mo' infections, mo' money."
等等
Wait!
你还是先洗洗
Maybe you want to wash
你那双小浣熊爪子吧
your little raccoon hands first.
放轻松
Oh, calm down.
我要是真感染了  早就挂了
If I had it, I'd be dead already.
各位听我说
Guys, listen up.
没空听  专注模式中
Can't listen, zone.
同时也不感兴趣
Also don't care.
下周是我和伯纳黛特初次约会的周年纪念
Next week is the anniversary of my first date with Bernadette.
彻底不感兴趣
Really don't care.
我想来点特殊的惊喜
I want to do something special,
希望大家能够一起参与
and I was hoping you guys could be a part of it.
你是干了什么坏事  现在想要弥补吧
Aw, what horrible thing are you trying to make up for?
我不过是先存点额度
Just putting something in the bank
留着下次干坏事时用
for what horrible thing I do next.
趁她还没回来  先说我的计划
Look, she's gonna be back any second, so here's the deal:
我在写一首歌
I'm writing a song, and I was hoping
希望可以大家演奏给她听
we could all play it for her together.
我喜欢这主意
Oh, I love that.
太有爱了
That is so beautiful.
谢尔顿
Sheldon?
我们什么时候来的芝士蛋糕工厂
When did we get to the Cheesecake Factory?
人人影视
YYeTs.com
生活大爆炸
第七季  第六集
霍华德想给伯纳黛特的惊喜真有心
It's really sweet what Howard wants to do for Bernadette.
对啊
Yeah.
你怎么就从没做点浪漫的事
Hey, how come you've never done anything romantic
来庆祝我们的初次约会呢
to celebrate our first date?
首先  你甩我的次数太多
Well, for starters, you've broken up with me so many times,
你的初次约会是指哪一次呢
which first date are we talking about?
这巴掌打得太响了
Ooh, somebody call the burn ward.
重回专注模式中
And back to the zone.
再说了  我经常为你制造浪漫呀
And besides, I do romantic things for you all the time.
倒是你能想出为我做过什么浪漫的事吗
Can you even name one romantic thing you've done for me?
我做过的可多了
I can name tons.
床事不算
Sex doesn't count.
对了  上次我们去住民宿算吧
I know, what about that Bed-and-Breakfast?
是我带你去的
Well, I took you there.
你所做的就只有...
All you did was...
我很清楚自己做了什么
I know what I did.
我估计他们得把那摇摇椅丢掉了
I bet they had to throw out that rocking chair.
要是我愿意  我也能变得很浪漫
You know, I can be romantic if I want to.
没关系啦
It's fine.
你能浪漫才怪
And also not true.
算了  你就等着瞧吧
Okay, just you wait and see.
我非浪漫得你魂飞魄散不可
I'm gonna romance your freakin' ass off.
这话真动听
That's beautiful.
敢问是莎士比亚的名言吗
Is that Shakespeare?
谢尔顿
Sheldon?
模式中
Zone.
等他从屋顶摔下来  就会知道自己走过了
He'll figure it out when he falls off the roof.
谢尔顿  我知道你沉浸在模式中
Sheldon, I know you're in the zone,
但你要喝茶吗
but do you want some tea?
好吧  真不敢相信我要这么说
All right, I can't believe I'm gonna say this,
你好几个小时都没说过话了
but you haven't spoken in hours
我开始有点担心了
and I'm starting to get worried.
拜托你说点什么吧
Please say something.
莱纳德  准备好五体投地
Leonard, prepare to be humbled
被本座的无上智慧吓哭吧
and weep at the glory of my genius.
我错了  你还是不说话的好
Nope, it was better before.
看看这白板
Look at it.
感觉就像我的智商生下了个娃
I feel like my mind just made a baby.
多可爱的宝宝啊
And it's beautiful.
它和人类宝宝不一样
It's not like human babies,
不会大吵大哭  浑身覆盖黏糊糊的液体
which are loud and covered in goop.
我的上帝啊  谢尔顿
Holy crap, Sheldon,
你这是想出了一个办法
did you just figure out a method
可以人工合成一种新型稳定超重元素吗
for synthesizing a new stable super-heavy element?
是吗
Did I?
这不可能呀
Well, that can't be right.
从来没有人成功过呢
No one's ever done that before.
除了我  我想出来了
Except me, because I just did it!
谢尔顿谢尔顿脑力无边
Sheldon and his brain-- yeah!
谢尔顿谢尔顿脑震八方
谢尔顿谢尔顿脑动武林
Sheldon and his brain-- yeah!
谢尔顿谢尔顿脑霸天下
谢尔顿谢尔顿
Sheldon and his brain...
没错  还是不说话的好
Yeah, definitely better before.
我给伯纳黛特写的歌快完工了
So I'm almost done writing the song for Bernadette.
你拉大提琴行吗
Are you cool playing the cello?
如果你是指乐意的"行"  那我可以
If by "cool" you mean "willing to," Yes.
如果是指我拉琴有"型"
If by "cool" You mean "cool,"
那你绝对是没见我拉大提琴的样子
clearly you've never seen me play the cello.
很好  那你弹尤克里里琴吧
Great. Will you play the ukulele?
好啊  我非常乐意炫一下我的速技
Of course. I'd be happy to shred it on my ax.
要不就弹你那把小得出奇的傻逼吉他也行
Or you could just play your tiny, ridiculous guitar.
好啦  我会弹得她心醉...
Fine. I will melt her heart.
脸也碎的
And her face!
各位先生
Gentlemen.
你们都听说了我的小突破吧
Uh, no doubt you heard about my little breakthrough.
如果你们计划
Now, if your plan
把我抬在肩上
is to hoist me on your shoulders
在小餐厅里游行一周  还请你们尽量不要
and carry me around the cafeteria, please refrain.
我个人不喜欢高处  我有晕动病
I don't care for heights, motion sickness
也不喜欢让你们的脖子蹭我的尊臀
or the thought of your necks touching my buttocks.
说真的  恭喜你  谢尔顿
Seriously, congratulations, Sheldon.
我在网上看到了你的论文
Yeah, I read your paper online.
创造一种新的重元素的方法相当启发人
That technique for creating a new heavy element is inspired.
谢谢
Oh, well, thank you.
信不信由你
Believe it or not,
我刚得知中国湖北
I just learned a Chinese research team
核子物理研究所的研究小组
at the Hubei Institute for Nuclear Physics
在回旋加速器上进行了测试
ran a test on a cyclotron,
结果相当喜人
and the results were extremely promising.
-谢尔顿  太不可思议了  -我知道
- Sheldon, that's incredible. - Yeah, I know!
他们称之为自共产党成立后最伟大的事
They called it the greatest thing since the Communist party.
不过我相当确信
Although I'm pretty sure that
是共产党让他们这样说的
the Communist party made them say that.
我爱中国
I like China.
他们知道如何让人守规矩
See, they know how to keep people in line.
接下来会怎样
So, what happens next?
更多的测试  更多的成功  更多的名望
Oh, more testing, more success, more fame.
别担心
But don't worry,
我会一如既往保持那颗踏踏实实的
I will remain the same down-to-earth humble Joe
谦卑之心
I've always been.
-太好了  -是的
- Good to know. - Yeah.
你的饼干本皇要了
Now give me that cookie;
我发现了新元素
I discovered an element.
感谢你能来
Thank you so much for coming.
你找对人了
You called the right person.
我相信我能设计出一个完美的浪漫之夜
I believe I have the perfect romantic evening
让你送给莱纳德
for you to give Leonard.
太好了  因为我真的是没辙了
Okay, good, 'cause I've been really struggling with this.
我相信你知道
As I'm sure you're aware,
最快的抓住男人心的方法是俘获他的...
the quickest way to a man's heart is through his...
"裤裆"  但莱纳德说床事不算
Pants, but Leonard says sex doesn't count.
可怜的女人
You poor thing.
箭袋里只有一支箭
You have one arrow in your quiver,
却被禁止使用
and you just can't use it.
幸运的是  另一个抓住男人心的方法是
Fortunately, another pathway to a man's heart
俘获他的胃
is through his stomach.
我不太愿意给他做饭
I don't know if I want to cook for him;
他在吃方面很挑剔
he's kind of a picky eater.
总是说  "太咸了"
I mean, "It's too salty.
"太干了"
It's too dry.
"这玩意简直是冻与焦之歌啊"
It's too burnt and frozen at the same time."
拜托
Wait, come on,
还有什么办法能让你春心荡漾的
what else would sweep you off your feet?
我一直有个关于跳舞的幻想
Well, I've always had this fantasy that involves dancing.
我与舞伴之间的
The sexual chemistry
暧昧感觉犹如电光四射
between my partner and me is electric.
老天啊老天
But boy, oh, boy,
我父亲却不赞同这段恋情
does my father not approve
直到他在舞蹈比赛上看到我们热舞一曲
until he sees us in the big dance competition.
拜托  这是电影《辣身舞》的剧情
Okay, that's just the plot for Dirty Dancing.
你还喜欢什么
What else would you love?
除上被帕特里克·斯威兹举过头顶之外
Other than being lifted over Patrick Swayze's head.
对了  你可以站在他的窗户外
Oh! Oh, uh, you could, uh, stand outside his window
将手提音响高高地举起放歌
with a boom box in the air.
这是电影《情到深处》的桥段
That's from Say Anything.
我是一个深闺寂寞的男人  没事就爱看电影
Look, I'm a lonely guy; I watch a lot of movies.
佩妮  如果你真的想要浪漫
Look, Penny, if you truly want to be romantic,
就得发自内心
it needs to come from you.
我明白  可为什么这么难呢
I get that, but why is this so hard?
可能是因为你从来不用做这些事
Well, you've probably never had to do this stuff
因为你既年轻又漂亮
'cause you're young and beautiful
男人对你趋之若鹜
and men have always thrown themselves at you.
是啊  我想为此难过一下
Yeah, I'm trying to be sad about that.
但我做不到
I can't.
我想想  下个是什么
Let's see, what's next?
好的  这个
Okay! Here.
这只马克笔
This is the Magic Marker
是我做出发现时使用的
I was using when I made the discovery.
我不觉得美国博物馆会要你的马克笔
I don't think the Smithsonian's gonna want your marker.
这就是我树屋不欢迎你的原因
And that's why you're not on a list for my tree fort.
猜猜《今日物理》
Ooh, guess who's getting an article
将写篇关于谁的报导
written about him in Physics Today?
给你个提示
I'll give you a hint.
你昨天为他测量过一颗可疑痣的直径
You measured the diameter of his suspicious mole yesterday.
谢尔顿  我真为你骄傲
Sheldon, I'm so proud of you.
这是应该的
Well, you should be.
我的发现的散播速度犹如星火燎原
My discovery is spreading like wildfire.
和我的痣不同  这颗痣保持稳定
Unlike my mole, which is holding steady
一直保持菜豆的大小
at the size of a navy bean.
下一个是什么
What's next?
这本是
This is the very copy
《化学物理手册》
of The Handbook of Chemistry and Physics
我就是用这本查询了
in which I looked up the reaction rates
钔的反应速率以及...
of mendelevium and...
-以及什么  -完了
- And what? - No.
完了  完了  完了
No, no, no, no.
出什么事了
What's wrong?
我犯了个可怕的错误
I've made a horrible mistake.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
这个表格是平方厘米制的
This table-- it's in square centimeters.
我看成了平方米
I read it as square meters.
知道这意味着什么吗
You know what that means?
美国人看不懂公制吗
That Americans can't handle the metric system?
艾米  我这是失之毫厘差之千里的错误
Amy, I was off by a factor of 10,000.
但是中国研究小组发现了元素
But the Chinese team found the element.
他们不应该发现的
Yeah, well, they shouldn't have.
我的计算是错的
My calculations were wrong.
元素之间肯定有
There must be some resonance
我不知道的某种共振
between the elements I didn't know about.
这么说你只是幸运吗
So you just got lucky?
谢尔顿·库珀从来不靠幸运[没上过床]
Sheldon Cooper does not get lucky!
咱们同病相怜  小哥哥
You and me both, brother.
这不重要
It doesn't matter.
因为你元素才会被发现
The element was found because of you,
这是突破性的成果
and that's groundbreaking.
重要的是
What matters is
我这辈子最伟大的科学成就
the greatest scientific achievement of my life
是建立在一个巨大的错误之上
is based on a blunder.
我不是天才  我是个骗子
I'm not a genius, I'm a fraud.
谢尔顿  在神经系统学里
You know, Sheldon, in neuroscience,
我们总是在大脑某处有所发现
we're forever finding something in one part of the brain
但地方和原来想的完全不一样
that we thought was someplace else.
这下可好
Oh, great.
现在我连骗子都不如了
Now I'm worse than a fraud.
我沦为生物学家之流了
I'm practically a biologist.
你别再为这件事自责了
You got to stop beating yourself up over this.
你虽然犯了错误  但也是个值得开心的错误
I mean, you made a mistake, but it was a happy mistake.
没什么好值得开心的
There's nothing happy about it.
这份功劳不是我应得的
I'm being given credit that I don't deserve.
人们经常会得到自己不应得的东西
Oh, people get things they don't deserve all the time.
看我的朋友是你就知道了
Look at me with you.
莱纳德  这件事会让我余生都痛苦不堪
No, Leonard, this is going to haunt me for the rest of my life.
每一个科学教室
Every science classroom,
每一张元素周期表  每一本教科书
every periodic table, every textbook--
这个错误会恶狠狠地瞪着我
this mistake will be staring back at me
就像那次你让库萨帕里帮你修眉毛的后果一样
like that time you let Koothrappali wax your eyebrows.
我要想办法解决这件事
I've got to find a way to stop this thing.
伙计  我觉得你没辙
Buddy, I don't think you can.
我的意思是  木已成舟  实难挽回
I mean, once it's out there, it's out there.
这件事就好比科学界的性爱影片流出
This thing is like the science equivalent of a sex tape.
老实说  我宁愿我的错是性爱影片
You know, frankly, I'd prefer a sex tape.
你不知道性爱影片是什么吧
You don't know what a sex tape is, do you?
不知道
No.
你们一定要在8点准时到达餐厅
Make sure you guys get to the restaurant by 8:00.
伯纳黛特会在8点半到达
Bernadette's meeting me there at 8:30
我可不想搞砸这次惊喜
and I don't want to blow the surprise.
-我们会准时到的  -收到
- We'll be there. - Got it.
对于这首歌  我有个问题
Now, uh, I have a question about the song.
我一直在想能不能
I was thinking at some point
在歌的某处给你加点说唱饶舌风
I could bust out a little rap.
嘿  哟  不  不  不要
N-N-N-No...
干嘛这样  你都还没听呢
Come on, come on, you haven't even heard it yet.
莱纳德  来点拍子
Leonard, give me a beat.
不要
I will not.
拜托啦
Please?
不要  我要的是浪漫好吗
No, I want this to be romantic.
会很浪漫啊
It will be!
歌词里没有叫任何人"婊子"
I don't call anyone a ho,
而且我唯一用到"我的小贱人"这个词
and the only time I use the phrase "my bitch,"
指的还是你
I'm referring to you.
他来了
There he is!
停下
Stop it.
别鼓掌赞扬我
Stop celebrating me!
还有无欢呼
And no woos!
不是说你  吴[无]博士  跟你没关系
Oh, not you, Dr. Woo. You're fine.
我想让大家知道
I want you all to know
你们没必要为我鼓掌喝彩
that you have no reason to applaud me.
我所谓的"突破"
My so-called breakthrough
不是因为我的聪明才智
wasn't the result of my genius.
那不过是我犯的低级错误而已
It was nothing more than a boneheaded mistake.
所以以后
So please refrain
请克制住你们想为此赞扬我的冲动
from praising me for it in the future.
什么  我不懂
Wh... I don't understand.
他们没发现那个元素吗
They didn't find the element?
不  他们发现了
Oh, no, they found the element.
不  不  停下
No, no, stop it!
我不需要你们这样的人
I don't need to take this admiration
来赞美崇拜我
from the likes of you people!
我怎么才能让他们不喜欢我呢
How do I make them stop loving me?
邀请他们跟咱们一起住
Invite them to live with us.
-伯纳黛特一定会感动死的  -对啊
- Boy, Bernadette is gonna love this. - Yeah.
有人为自己做这么浪漫的事  感觉一定很棒
It must be nice to have someone do something so romantic.
够了  你知道什么是不浪漫吗
Okay, you know what's not romantic?
正面嘲讽别人[在别人脸上蹭来蹭去]
Rubbing it in someone's face.
老实说这的确是
Actually, it can be,
但我之前说了  床事不算
but I told you sex doesn't count.
我开始担心伯纳黛特了
I'm getting worried about Bernadette.
我要打给她问一下
I'm gonna call and check on her.
国家科学基金会
The National Science Foundation
想给我一大笔研究基金
wants to give me a substantial grant.
-这是大事啊  -我知道
- Oh, that's a big deal. - I know.
这场恶梦要何时才能结束
When will this nightmare end?
我知道你觉得受不起这些关注
Hey, I get that you feel bad about all the attention,
但你做的事真的很了不起
but still, what you did is amazing.
-我们为你感到骄傲  -除了我
- We're really proud of you. - I'm not.
你不是吗
You're not?
谢尔顿  我一直在考虑这件事
Sheldon, I've been thinking about it,
你说得对
and you're right.
这份功劳不是你应得的
You don't deserve any credit.
你不过是看错了表上一些数字
All you did was misread some numbers on a table.
那还是一张非常简单的表
A very easy table, too.
老实说  我为你感到羞愧
Honestly, I'm embarrassed for you.
这是我这辈子听过最浪漫的话了
That's the most romantic thing I've ever heard.
靠  大家都比我会耍浪漫
Damn it, everyone's better at this than me.
恭喜你  福勒博士
Congratulations, Dr. Fowler.
我的树屋欢迎你
You just made the fort.
各位  妮妮的实验室出事了
Guys, there w-was an accident at Bernie's lab.
天啊  她没事吧
Oh, my God, is she okay?
没事  不过她被送去医院隔离了
Yeah, but she's at the hospital in quarantine.
-什么  -可怜的伯纳黛特
- What? - Poor Bernadette.
我不想雪上加霜  但我刚获得加薪了
I hate to pile on the bad news, but I just got a raise.
天啊  妮妮  发生什么事了
Oh, my God, Bernie, what happened?
我只能说下次当你把
Well, let's just say the next time you move
12瓶浣熊病毒放进冰箱时
a dozen vials of raccoon virus to the fridge,
最好分两次拿
make two trips.
你确定你没事吗
You're sure you're okay?
没事  这只是防范措施而已
Yeah, it's just a precaution.
如果我有事
If there was a problem,
我早就连眼珠子吐出来了
I'd be throwing up out of my eyeballs by now.
抱歉我搞砸了我们的约会
Sorry I messed up our date.
不用担心
No, don't worry about it.
我把约会带这来了
I brought the date here.
各位快进来
Guys, come on in.
这是怎么回事
What's all this?
今晚是我们第一次约会的周年纪念日
Well, tonight is the anniversary of our first date,
我为你写了首歌来庆祝
and I wanted to celebrate it by writing a song for you.
华仔
Howie.
谢尔顿  快过来
Sheldon, get over here!
她可能会传染人
She might be contagious.
你觉得我今天过得还不够糟吗
Don't you think I'm having a rough enough day?
谢尔顿
Sheldon!
* 如果身旁没有你 *
* If I didn't have you *
* 生活无趣失重心 *
* Life would be blue *
* 《神秘博士》没话亭*
* I'd be Dr. Who without the TARDIS *
电视剧《神秘博士》中的多功能电话亭
对这剧有举足轻重的意义
你们有没有觉得她看着像是被感染了
Is it me, or does she not look so good?
* 也像蜡烛没灯芯*
* A candle without a wick *
* 沃森没了克里克 *
* A Watson without a Crick *
沃森与克里克与另一名搭档一起发现了
DNA分子的结构
* 像我衣服少领结 *
* I'd be one of my outfits without a dick-ie *
* 起司没有通心面 *
* I'd be cheese without the mac *
* 像乔布斯没搭档 *
* Jobs without the Wozniak *
苹果公司的创始人
乔布斯与好搭档沃兹尼亚克
* 没有了你就像是 *
* I'd be solving exponential equations *
* 用少底的计算器  来解指数方程式 *
* That use bases not found on your calculator *
* 难度加倍解不出 *
* Making it much harder to crack *
* 像个原子没有弹 *
* I'd be an atom without a bomb  *
* 像个点儿少了康 *
* A dot without the com *
* 而且还在跟妈住 *
* And I'd probably still live with my mom *
* 他还会在跟妈住 *
* And he'd probably still live with his mom *
* 打从初次遇见你  一切天翻又地覆 *
* Ever since I met you, you turned my world around *
* 我的梦想与希望  都有你在支持我 *
* You supported all my dreams and all my hopes *
* 你若是那铀235  那我就是铀238 *
* You're like uranium-235 and I'm uranium-238 *
* 难分离的同位素 *
* Almost inseparable isotopes *
* 我从没能想象到 *
* I couldn't have imagined *
* 此生能如此幸福 *
* How good my life would get *
* 而我幸福的起点 *
* From the moment *
* 是在初次遇见你 *
* That I met you *
* 伯纳黛特 *
* Bernadette *
华仔
Oh, Howie.
* 如果身旁没有你 *
* If I didn't have you *
* 百无聊赖失寄托 *
* Life would be dreary *
* 像弦理论失了弦 *
* I'd be string theory without any string *
* 二进位中少了1 *
* I'd be binary code without a one *
* 阴极射线管没枪 *
* A cathode ray tube without an electron gun *
* 《萤火虫》《巴菲》《复联》没了导演乔斯·惠登 *
* I'd be Firefly, Buffy and Avengers without Joss Whedon *
电视剧《萤火虫》《吸血鬼猎人巴菲》
电影《复仇者联盟》导演都是乔斯·惠登
* 会多说克林贡语 *
* I'd speak a lot more Klingon *
* 黄道吉日今宜死 *
* Heghlu'meH QaQ jajvam *
克林贡语版的"today is a good day to die"
下一句其实是"送我们的敌人去见祖宗吧"
* 他还会在跟妈住 *
* And he'd definitely still live with his mom *
* 打从初次遇见你  一切天翻又地覆 *
* Ever since I met you, you turned my world around *
* 当我挚爱与挚友 *
* You're my best friend and my lover *
* 要电动才能生磁  而磁变才会生电 *
* We're like changing electric and magnetic fields *
* 如果没有了对方 *
* You can't have one *
* 只有自己便不行 *
* Without the other *
* 我从没能想象到 *
* I couldn't have imagined *
* 此生能如此幸福 *
* How good my life would get *
* 而我幸福的起点  是在初次遇见你 *
* From the moment that I met you *
* 伯纳黛特 *
* Bernadette *
* 我们从没想象到 *
* Oh, we couldn't have imagined *
* 此生能如此幸福 *
* How good our lives would get *
* 我们幸福的起点  是在初次遇见你 *
* From the moment that we met you *
* 伯纳黛特 *
* Bernadette. *
华仔  这歌太棒了
Howie, that was amazing!
我听得都发抖了
Look, I'm shaking.
我就知道她被感染了   我先闪了
She's sick, I knew it. Bye!
不得不说
I have to say,
这是你做过最好吃的一次拉面
this is the best top Ramen you've ever made.
我发现了一个神秘原料
I discovered a secret ingredient:
叫"调味包"
the flavor packet.
那包玩意还真不是浪得虚名
That sucker is well named.
好啦  小宝贝
All right, lover boy.
做好准备  狂风暴雨般的浪漫
Get ready, 'cause there is a crap storm of romance
将对你席卷而来
coming your way.
别这样  我会"感动"到哭
Stop it, you're gonna make me cry.
好吧  既然你这么有信心
All right. You seem pretty confident.
必须的
Oh, I am.
如果你沿着这花径走
Maybe if you follow this trail,
或许就能知道原因
you'll see why.
-还有玫瑰花瓣啊  -没错
- Oh, rose petals. - Yes.
所有花中
The most beautiful
最美丽  贵得吓死人的花
and shockingly expensive of all the flowers.
你还铺了床
You made the bed?
真使出浑身解数啊
You really are pulling out all the stops.
我费了好大一番心思
Okay, I gave this a lot of thought,
终于找到了一样能向你表达
and I finally found something to show you
我深深爱意的礼物
how much I love you.
是第一版的
It's a first edition of
《银河系漫游指南》
Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy.
我记得这是你从小到大最爱的书
I remember it was your favorite book growing up.
太棒了
This is great.
谢谢你
It... thank you.
这份礼物太重了
It's... so much.
怎么了
What?
-没有啊  我很喜欢  -不对
- Nothing. I love it. - No.
你表情不对劲  这书哪里有问题
Something's going on. What's wrong with it?
我记得你说过有一本初版的这书
I remember you saying how great it would be
会有多棒
to have a first edition.
是的  我是说过
It's true, I-I did.
我说这句话
I did say that...
是我们一起在二手书店
when we were at the used bookstore together
我买下第一版的这书时说的
and I saw the first edition and I bought it.
-天啊  我太差劲了  -没事没事
- Oh, my God, I am the worst! - No, no, it's okay.
你已经很贴心了
It's really thoughtful.
不  才不是
No, it's not! I mean...
你所做的一切才是最贴心的
What's thoughtful is everything you do.
这里  你看这些
Here, you know what? Look at this.
你看  这是你帮我买的机票
Look, here's the... the plane ticket you bought me
当时我假期没钱买机票回老家
when I was too poor to go home for the holidays.
这是你放在我挡风玻璃上的玫瑰花
And the rose you left on my windshield...
就耍耍浪漫
just because.
这是你在我们第一次做爱后隔天
Here's the-the thank-you letter you wrote me
你写给我的感谢信
after the first time I slept with you.
整整十一页呢
All 11 pages of it.
没想到你把这些都保留下来了
Can't believe you saved all this stuff.
当然啦
Of course I did.
都是你的心意
It's you.
过来
Come here.
那是验孕棒吗
Is that a pregnancy test?
就留了第一根
Oh, yeah, just the first one.
我当然不会全留下
I didn't save them all.
真不敢相信我看错了这表格
I can't believe I read this table wrong.
都怪你
I blame you.
我  关我什么事
Me? What did I do?
你害我分心
You distract me.
从遇见你的那一刻  你就让我分心
I've been distracted since the moment I met you.
对不起嘛
Sorry.
没错
Well, you should be.
因为我脑海里
Because all I can think about
满满得都是想吻你的冲动
is how much I want to kiss you.
而且不是吻脸颊  是要吻嘴唇
And not just on the cheek, but on the mouth.
像所有爸爸妈妈做的那样
Like mommies and daddies do.
谢尔顿
Oh, Sheldon.
艾米
Amy?
Amy.
你听到我说的了吗
Did you hear what I said?
没空说话  专注模式中
Can't talk, in the zone.